Rajat Varma

fullstack web developer, designer

GitHub Profile
LinkedIn
Email

Website

about

I'm Rajat, a first-year student at Ashoka University, pursuing Computer Science. I am a **web and app developer** and am interested in other fields of computing such as **Artificial Intelligence** and **Algorithm Design**. Apart from this, I have been playing the **piano** for about 11 years and playing **badminton** at an intermediate level.

experience

Software Dev Intern @ Codon Software Ltd.

05/2019-07/2019

- Full Stack Wed Development project, using **Django** and **VueJS** to create a dashboard for retail store owners to manage inventory
- Implemented backend using Django Models and REST APIs

Python Dev Intern @ Codon Softwares Ltd.

04/2020-09/2020

- Chatbot development, using Python and DialogFlow
- Automated the training process of the bot using Python script
- Hosted an accessible API on Heroku

President @ Network of Digital Enthusiasts (NODE) club at DPS Gurgaon

05/2020-02/2021

- Organised multiple workshops on web development
- Coordinated and lead the school teams to victory in tech symposium
- Managed the IT and Design departments of various other events: MUNs and TED events

App Developer @ Codon Softwares Ltd.

07/2021-09/2021

- Built a Design of Experiments API using R and Plumber
- Created an AWS Lambda for email handling, using NodeJS and DynamoDB
- Developed and designed the UX for an eCommerce a using React Native. Available on Play Store

education

Ashoka University (2021-2024) **BSc.** Computer Science (Hons.)

Delhi Public School, Gurgaon (CBSE):

- 12th Class: 93.8% (2021) (PCM+CS)
- 10th Class: 95.4% (2019)

certifications

- Python For Everybody (Specialization): University of Michigan (October 2018)
- Programming Fundamentals and Logic: Duke University (April 2018)
- Career Edge: TCS iON Learning (June 2020)
- Machine Learning with Python: IBM (July 2018)
- UX Professional Certificate: Google (July 2021)

skills

Development

Python- SciPy, Pandas, NumPy, intermediate scripting, AWS Lambdas

Advanced

Web Development- React+Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Heroku and Netlify

Advanced

Databases- MySQL, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB

Beginner

App Development- React Native, Flutter+Dart, Kotlin Intermediate

Design

UI/UX design- Adobe XD, Figma, Photoshop

Intermediate

Graphic Design- Krita, Blender, Illustrator

Intermediate